# María Alejandra Pazos-Smith

CLINICAL PSYCHOLOGIST



malejandrapazos@gmail.com



07780066109



Chippenham, Wiltshire, United Kingdom

## **PROFILE**

A motivated psychologist with a meticulous approach, reliable, self motivated and hard working. Always ready to listen, acquire knowledge and apply new techniques into the workspace. With 4 years experience as a professional practitioner in patients mental health research, as well as

# SKILLS

- Analytical Thinking
- Team Leadership
- Active Listening

- Initiative
- Teamwork

- Project Planning

## LANGUAGES

## **EDUCATION**

June 2017 - February 2022

Clinical Psychology with Bachelor in General Psychology, Universidad del Istmo, Guatemala City

June 2020 - November 2020

Diploma in Forensic Psychology, Universidad del Istmo, Guatemala City

## **EXPERIENCE**

June 2023 - present day Wood Lane, Chippenham

June 2017 - February 2022 Guatemala City

June 2021 Guatemala city

June 2020 Guatemala city

June 2019 Guatemala city

June 2018 Guatemala city

#### **Teaching Assistant (TA)**

At Charter Primary School, Special Educational Needs (SEN) Resource Base. Part time

### **Professional Psychologist Practitioner**

Clinic of Psychopedagogical and Psychological Care of the Faculty of Humanities at "Universidad del Istmo" - Psychological therapy is provided to 8 patients (children, adolescents and adults).

#### **Professional Work**

Create a manual for the Development of Emotional Intelligence and Resilience in 6th grade students at "Mama Margarita" School Center in Guatemala.

#### **Professional Work**

Training for "Esperanza Juvenil" (A Guatemalan Institution that supports children and young people with limited resources to overcome adverse circumstances and become successful professionals) staff, in charge of teaching children and adolescents who reside in the institution's facilities, on general implications in children/adolescents with pharmacological treatment.

## **Professional Psychologist Practitioner**

Municipal Program for Children and Adolescents at risk of street

## **Professional Psychologist Practitioner**

Child Protection Society

#### About me

Hobbies

Crochet, Knitting, Embroidery, Drawing, Painting, Baking, Cooking, Sports (Basketball), Music, Movies, Dog lover